Guide to the H.M. Chester Photograph Collection 1892-1910, undated PR 131
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
H.M. Chester Photograph Collection
1892-1910, undated
PR 131
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
3.78 Linear feet (9 boxes)
Collection of glass negatives documenting H.M. Chester's extensive travels across the United States and to its borders from 1892-1910. Views of expositions, railroads, prominent residences, national parks, and tourist attractions make up the bulk of the collection which focuses most heavily on California, Colorado, Michigan, New York, Washington, and Yellowstone and Yosemite National Parks.
Chester, H.M. (Herbert M.), b. 1858
Provenance
Gift of American Institute of the City of New York on October 4, 1933.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to 30 photocopies per day per person. Suitability of the original for photocopying is at the discretion of the staff. Neither blueprints nor tracings can be copied under any circumstances. Duplication of large-format items will be done by the house photographer. See Print Room guidelines for details.
Biographical Note
Herbert M. Chester was born in New York in 1858 to Emeline Merritt and John H. Chester. By 1870 the family had moved to North Stonington, Connecticut. Little is known about Chester's life except that he traveled extensively throughout the United States between 1892 and 1909 to California, Utah, New Mexico, Washington, Michigan, New York, and other states, as well as to the Canadian and Mexican borders.
Scope and Content Note
The H.M. Chester Photograph Collection consists of glass negatives, measuring 4 x 5 to 6 ½ x 8 ½ inches, depicting prominent residences, tourist attractions, railroads, fairs, and natural landscapes across the United States, but especially in California, Colorado, Michigan, New York, Washington, and at Yellowstone National Park. The collection spans the period from 1892-1910; most of the negatives are undated but were probably created close to this time period. The collection is arranged alphabetically by state and thereunder by city or other geographical feature; views of the Pan-American Exposition in Buffalo have been filed under Niagara Falls/Buffalo because the majority of the photographs relate to Niagara Falls. Images of Yellowstone National Park have been filed under Wyoming. Views of Mexico are filed at the end of the states. Views of unidentified locations have been filed in a miscellaneous subseries at the end of the collection; they are organized by subject. One box of oversized negatives has been filed at the end of the collection; it also contains the photographic prints. It is unclear whether the photographs in this collection were taken by H.M. Chester or by another member of his traveling party. Some numbers have been subdivided by letter due to the addition of discovered negatives after the collection was processed.
The collection includes views of the Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition held in Seattle in 1909, the Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition held in Portland, Oregon in 1905, and the Pan-American Exposition held in 1901 in Buffalo (and associated hydroelectric projects at Niagara Falls). The collection includes photographs of H.M. Chester, his wife, and their fellow travelers at many of the featured locations. California is the most heavily represented state in the collection. A series of Yosemite National Park and Mount Tamalpais landscape photographs are complemented by more urban photographs taken in Los Angeles and at San Francisco and Oakland landmarks. In New York, Rochester and Niagara Falls are the most heavily represented areas, although some images of New York City buildings and events such as the Dewey Celebration and the Grant's Tomb Dedication Parade are included.
Foreign views on the Canadian side of Niagara Falls and of the Mexican border, probably near Tijuana, are also present. The Connecticut negatives, of which several are oversized, consist primarily of images of a farm in North Stonington, Connecticut (which is probably the Chester family farm) as well as photographs of H.M. Chester and his wife.
The miscellaneous subseries includes photographs of individuals, animals, unidentified landscapes, ships, streetscapes, and two 1907 flower shows. A few portraits of a man identified as W.E. McCarthy are also present.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically by state; thereunder they are filed by city or geographical feature and then alphabetically by major features. Mexico is filed at the end of the states, followed by miscellaneous negatives. Oversize negatives and the three photographic contact prints are filed in box 9.
Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition (1909: Seattle, Wash.) -- Pictorial works; Chester family; Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition (1905: Portland, Or.) -- Pictorial works; Pan-American Exposition (1901: Buffalo, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Catskill Mountains (N.Y.) -- Description and travel -- Pictorial works; Contact prints; Glass negatives; Niagara Falls (N.Y. and Ont.) -- Description and travel -- Pictorial works; North Stonington (Conn.); United States -- Description and travel -- Pictorial works; Yellowstone National Park -- Description and travel -- Pictorial works; Yosemite National Park (Calif.) -- Description and travel -- Pictorial works
- California
  - Alcatraz Island
    - Navy Prisons [View of Alcatraz Island and Buildings, San Francisco Bay in foreground], undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - On the West [View of Alcatraz Island, San Francisco Bay in foreground], undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alhambra
    - Residence, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Barstow
    - Main Street, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Boyes [Hot] Springs
    - Three Graces - Bathers at Beach [Young women posing beside pool], undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bathers at Boyes Springs, undated (Box 1, Folder 6a-b)
  - Coronado
    - Seals at Coronado Beach, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Glendora
    - Mr. Easley's House, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - House at Glendora, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bungalow on Pillies Ranch, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - House on Pillies Ranch, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hollywood
    - De Longprees (The Artist) Residence, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Whitney Residence, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Idlewild
    - Large Red & White Oleander Tree, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - La Jolla
    - Anna Held Cottage, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bathing Beach, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Caves at La Jolla, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
    - Episcopal Church, undated (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
    - G.A. Greeley & daughter bathing, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - The Motor Car, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - The White Lady Cave, undated (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - La Mirada
    - The Harvester [horses pulling farm equipment], undated (Box 1, Folder 26-33)
  - Los Angeles
    - The 100 Year Old Palm Tree [showing streetcar], undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Residence on Adams Street, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Log Cabin - Adams Street, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
      General note
      See also: 562, Box 9
    - Log Cabin - Adams Street, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - China Town [Chinatown - child, adult, and storefront], undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - China Town [Chinatown storefront reading "WAH LEE & Co."], undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Hill St. M.E. Church [Methodist Episcopal Church], undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - East Lake Park, undated (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
    - Little Cottage where we stopped - "Mrs. Pettigrews", undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - 288 North Sichel Street (G.A. Greeley Family), undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Old Mission Church, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Major General Otis Residence, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Plaza, undated (Box 1, Folder 47-48)
    - Mr. Posey's Residence (Chester Place), undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Rubber Trees, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Mr. Singleton's Residence, undated (Box 1, Folder 51-52)
    - Palm Drive leading to Singleton Court, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Soldier's Monument - 5th Street [Pershing Square Park], undated (Box 1, Folder 54-55)
    - Falls in Westlake Park, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - View at Westlake Park, undated (Box 1, Folder 57-63)
  - Mount Lowe
    - Canyon, undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Electric Railroad, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Electric road running to Mt. Lowe, undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Granite Gateway, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Highest Point of Mt. Lowe, undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Mount Tamalpais
    - Incline R.R. to Echo Mts., 1901 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Point of Rocks, undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - View of Railroad, undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Bow Knot, undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Hotel from Top of Mountains, undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Looking down from Mt. Tamalpais, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Observatory on Top of Mt. Tamalpais, undated (Box 2, Folder 75-76)
    - Snap on the cars while on the turn [Muir Woods train], undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Oakland
    - Congregational Church (where Sunshine was married), undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - St. Julian Hotel, undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Borax Smith Residence (East Oakland), undated (Box 2, Folder 80-81)
    - Bronze lion in front of Borax Smith's Residence, undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Borax Smith's desert hut that he occupied in the Death Valley Desert, undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Borax Smith's Deer Park, undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Mrs. H.M. Chester's niece with Borax Smith's Dogs, undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Pasadena
    - The Grotto, undated (Box 2, Folder 86-87)
    - Residence on Orange Grove Avenue, undated (Box 2, Folder 88-90)
  - Redlands
    - Mr. Smiley's Residence, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Smiley Heights, undated (Box 2, Folder 92-93)
  - Riverside
    - 2 Orange Trees, undated (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Arch's Residence on Magnolia Avenue, undated (Box 2, Folder 95-96)
    - Band Stand in Park, undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Cactus in Park, undated (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Century Plant, undated (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Mr. & Mrs. Cushing and Mr. & Mrs. Chester Glenwood, undated (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Glenwood Tavern, undated (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Large Tree in front of Glenwood Tavern, undated (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Large Palms on Magnolia Avenue, undated (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Magnolia Avenue, undated (Box 2, Folder 104-106)
    - Original Washington Naval Orange Tree, undated (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - View from Victoria Hill, undated (Box 2, Folder 108-110)
  - San Francisco
    - Ruins of City Hall, [1906] (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Cliff House, undated (Box 2, Folder 112-113)
    - The Dewey Monument, undated (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - The Flood Building, undated (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Goat Island - Naval Training Station between Oakland and San Francisco [now Yerba Buena Island], undated (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Foot of Market Street, undated (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Market & 5th Street, undated (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Old Mission Church, undated (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Seal Rocks, undated (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Entrance to Sutro Park, undated (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Old Fort Sutro Park, undated (Box 2, Folder 122-123)
  - San Gabriel
    - San Gabriel Mission, undated (Box 2, Folder 124-126)
  - Santa Catalina Island
    - Santa Catalina Island, undated (Box 2, Folder 127-129)
    - (View of) Catalina Island Landing, undated (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - Glass Bottom Boat, undated (Box 3, Folder 131-133)
    - Harbor, undated (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Main Street, undated (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - The Needles, undated (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Indians at the Needles, undated (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Seal Rocks, undated (Box 3, Folder 138-141)
    - Stage Coach to Catalina Island, undated (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Street of Tents, undated (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Young Ladies Rowing, undated (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Residence, undated (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Senator Jones' Residence, undated (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Soldiers' Home, undated (Box 3, Folder 147-148)
    - Soldiers' Home - "Waiting in line for their mail", undated (Box 3, Folder 149-150)
  - Sausalito
    - Sausalito, undated (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Sausalito City, undated (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Sausalito Landing, undated (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - Sonoma
    - The Arrow [Building], undated (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Cactus Hedge, undated (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - H.M. Chester Group at Sonoma, undated (Box 3, Folder 156-157)
    - Sonoma Mission, undated (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - General Valeri's Oak, undated (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Yosemite National Park
    - The Arch Rock, undated (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Bridal Veil Falls, undated (Box 3, Folder 161-163)
    - Bridal Veil Falls & The 3 Graces, undated (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - Bridal Veil Falls & Merced River & 3 Graces, undated (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Bridal Veil Falls, the 3 Graces & El Capitan, undated (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - El Capitan & Merced River, undated (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - The Fallen Monarch, undated (Box 3, Folder 168a-d)
    - Mr. H.M. Chester Group at Yosemite Valley, undated (Box 3, Folder 169a)
    - Mrs. H.M. Chester (Emma) at Grizzly Giant, undated (Box 3, Folder 169b-g)
      See also: 563, Box 9
    - Glazier Point & Grizzly Peak, undated (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - Happy Isles, undated (Box 3, Folder 171a)
    - Log Cabin, Big Trees (Wowona), undated (Box 3, Folder 171b)
    - Mirror Lake, undated (Box 3, Folder 172-174)
    - Nevada Falls, undated (Box 3, Folder 175-177a)
    - Old Grizzly - Full size, undated (Box 3, Folder 177b)
    - Stella Lake, undated (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - Stage at Camp Curry, undated (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - Stage driving through trees, undated (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - Vernal Falls, undated (Box 4, Folder 181-182)
    - Watering the Horses on the Road, undated (Box 4, Folder 183)
    - Yosemite Falls from the Road, undated (Box 4, Folder 184)
    - Yosemite Falls from the soldiers' camp, undated (Box 4, Folder 185-186)
  - Miscellaneous
    - G.A. Greeley's Dog, undated (Box 4, Folder 187)
    - Hotel Roclinda, undated (Box 4, Folder 188)
- Colorado
  - Basalt
    - View at Basalt, undated (Box 4, Folder 189)
  - Colorado Springs Region
    - Mr. H.M. Chester on Burro at Cheyenne Falls, undated (Box 4, Folder 190)
    - Falls, Cheyenne Canon, undated (Box 4, Folder 191-194)
    - Cheyenne Canon, undated (Box 4, Folder 195-196)
    - Major Dome Peaks - Glen Eyrie, undated (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Ute Pass - People on Donkey, undated (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Ute Pass - Rainbow Falls, undated (Box 4, Folder 199)
    - Webber & North Platt Avenue - High School, undated (Box 4, Folder 200)
  - Denver
    - City Hall, undated (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Capitol Building, undated (Box 4, Folder 202-203)
  - New Castle
    - Burning Mountain, undated (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - Pike's Peak Region
    - Cave of the Winds, undated (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - Williams Canon - Cave of the Winds, undated (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - The Gateway, undated (Box 4, Folder 207-208)
    - Gateway Pikes Peak (in the distance), undated (Box 4, Folder 209)
    - Pikes Peak & Manitou, undated (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Balance Rock, undated (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - Cathedral Spires, undated (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - Canon - Rocky Mountains, undated (Box 4, Folder 213)
    - Tower of Babylon, undated (Box 4, Folder 214)
- Connecticut
  - New London
    - [Boat by sign for "Fort Griswold House and Cottages"], undated (Box 4, Folder 215a)
    - Bridge over Thames River, undated (Box 4, Folder 215b-c)
  - North Stonington
    - Mrs. H.M. Chester, Comrades - Emma, Horse & Cow, undated (Box 4, Folder 216-217a)
      See also: Box 9, 553-558
    - Mr. H.M. Chester and Horse, undated (Box 4, Folder 217b)
- District of Columbia
  - Washington
    - Canal, undated (Box 4, Folder 218)
    - The Capitol, undated (Box 4, Folder 219)
    - G.A.R. Posts [in parade], undated (Box 4, Folder 220)
    - G.A.R. Post in parade, undated (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - G.A.R. Views at Washington - Old Knickerbockers, undated (Box 4, Folder 222)
    - Washington Monument, undated (Box 4, Folder 223)
    - Washington Statue [with G.A.R. Hospital carriage], undated (Box 4, Folder 224)
- Massachusetts
  - Holyoke
    - View at Holyoke, Connecticut River, undated (Box 4, Folder 225)
  - Springfield
    - Kenelworth Castle - A Castle in Springfield, undated (Box 4, Folder 226-227)
- Michigan
  - Detroit
    - City Hall, undated (Box 4, Folder 228)
    - City Hall Square, undated (Box 4, Folder 229)
    - Ferry Boat on Detroit River, undated (Box 4, Folder 230)
    - Fountains Temple Theater, undated (Box 4, Folder 231)
    - Memorial Cannon, undated (Box 4, Folder 232)
    - Soldiers Monument, undated (Box 4, Folder 233)
  - Mount Clemens
    - City Hall, undated (Box 4, Folder 234)
    - Fenton Hotel, undated (Box 4, Folder 235)
    - Fenton Hotel and Mt. Clemens, undated (Box 4, Folder 236)
    - Mt. Clemens View, undated (Box 4, Folder 237-238)
    - Soldiers in Camp, undated (Box 4, Folder 239-240)
    - View on River Road, undated (Box 4, Folder 241)
- Minnesota
  - Minneapolis
    - Minnehaha Falls, undated (Box 5, Folder 242a-b)
  - St. Paul
    - Capitol Building, undated (Box 5, Folder 243)
- New Mexico
  - Albuquerque
    - Indians, undated (Box 5, Folder 244-246)
  - Arcadia
    - Railroad Station, undated (Box 5, Folder 247-248)
    - The Old Spanish Bill at Lucky Baldwin Ranch, undated (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - Rowe
    - Cottage, undated (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Las Vegas Hotel, undated (Box 5, Folder 251)
- New York
  - Catskill Mountains
    - Cairo – Cairo View, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 252-254)
    - Cairo – Cairo Depot, undated (Box 5, Folder 255)
    - Cairo – Cairo Flyer in Motion, undated (Box 5, Folder 256)
    - Cairo – Cairo Flyer at Station, undated (Box 5, Folder 257)
    - Cairo – Charely & Pigs, undated (Box 5, Folder 258)
    - Cairo – Cows in field, mountains in distance, undated (Box 5, Folder 259)
    - Cairo – Cows in Mr. Walter's field, undated (Box 5, Folder 260-261)
    - Cairo – Shady Glen Mountains in Distance, undated (Box 5, Folder 262)
    - Cairo – Walters Hotel, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 263-264)
    - East Wyndam, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 265-266)
    - Falls – Glen Falls House - Purling, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 267)
    - Falls – Gorge High Falls, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 268-269)
    - Falls – High Falls, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 270-271)
    - Falls – Kauterskill Falls, undated (Box 5, Folder 272)
    - Falls – Kauterskill Falls, undated (Box 5, Folder 273)
    - Falls – Lower Falls - Purling Glen, undated (Box 5, Folder 274)
    - Falls – Upper Falls - Purling Glen, undated (Box 5, Folder 275)
    - Lava Beds – Lava Bed Bridge, undated (Box 5, Folder 276)
    - Lava Beds – Lava Beds, undated (Box 5, Folder 277)
    - Lava Beds – View from the Lava Bed, undated (Box 5, Folder 278-279)
    - Leeds – Horses and Carriages near Leeds, View of, undated (Box 5, Folder 280-281)
    - Leeds – Old Bridge, undated (Box 5, Folder 282)
    - Leeds – Old Stone Bridge, undated (Box 5, Folder 283-289)
    - Otis Railroad – Otis Elevated Railroad, undated (Box 5, Folder 290)
    - Otis Railroad – Otis Railroad, undated (Box 5, Folder 291)
    - Water Bodies – Green Lake, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 292)
    - Water Bodies – Kauterskill Creek, undated (Box 5, Folder 293)
    - Water Bodies – Pond near High Park, undated (Box 5, Folder 294)
    - Miscellaneous – Beautiful Clouds, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 295)
    - Miscellaneous – Catskill, undated (Box 5, Folder 296)
    - Miscellaneous – Clouds, undated (Box 5, Folder 297)
    - Miscellaneous – Charlie's Team, undated (Box 5, Folder 298)
    - Miscellaneous – Old Bridge near High Peak House, undated (Box 5, Folder 299)
    - Miscellaneous – Old Mountain House, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 300)
    - Miscellaneous – Range - Finch's Dog, undated (Box 5, Folder 301)
    - Miscellaneous – Steeple Jack rigging a Derrick, undated (Box 5, Folder 302)
    - Miscellaneous – West Shore Bridge, undated (Box 5, Folder 303)
  - New York City - Manhattan
    - Events – [Columbian Celebration] 57th Street Arch, [1892] (Box 5, Folder 304)
    - Events – Dewey Parade - Circle - 58th Street and 8th Avenue, 1899 Sep. 30 (Box 5, Folder 305)
    - Events – Grant Parade [Grant's Tomb dedication parade], [1897] (Box 5, Folder 306)
    - Events – President McKinley [in Grant's Tomb dedication parade], [1897] (Box 5, Folder 307)
    - Street scenes – 14th Street East from 5th, undated (Box 6, Folder 308)
    - Streets scenes – Battery, undated (Box 6, Folder 309)
    - Street scenes – North From Union Square, undated (Box 6, Folder 310)
    - Street scenes – Wall Street and Trinity Church, undated (Box 6, Folder 311)
    - Structures – 48th Street Church - Laying the Stone [large crowd], undated (Box 6, Folder 312-313)
    - Structures – Bridge of Sighs, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 314)
    - Structures – Columbus Statue, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 315)
    - Structures – Fifth Avenue Hotel, undated (Box 6, Folder 316)
    - Structures – Herald Building, undated (Box 6, Folder 317-318)
    - May Pole in Central Park, undated (Box 6, Folder 319)
    - Structures – Pumping House - Central Park, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 320)
    - Miscellaneous – Bowling Green, undated (Box 6, Folder 321)
    - Miscellaneous – (Elevated Tracks), undated (Box 6, Folder 322)
    - Miscellaneous – Snow Views, undated (Box 6, Folder 323-327)
  - New York City – Brooklyn
    - Brooklyn Bridge, undated (Box 6, Folder 328-329)
    - Coney Island, undated (Box 6, Folder 330)
  - New York City – Queens
    - Bathing Rockaway, undated (Box 6, Folder 331-332)
    - C.J. Johnson Diving, undated (Box 6, Folder 333-336)
    - [Concession Stands on Beach], undated (Box 6, Folder 337-340)
    - [People on Beach], undated (Box 6, Folder 341-342)
    - [People on Beach], undated (Box 6, Folder 343-346)
    - [Swimmer in water], undated (Box 6, Folder 347)
    - Tots [at] Rockaway, undated (Box 6, Folder 348)
  - Niagara Falls / Buffalo - The Pan-American Exposition (1901)
    - American Falls – American Side, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 349)
    - American Falls – Canadian Side, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 350-352)
    - American Falls – From Goat Island, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 353)
    - American Falls - From the Maid of the Mist, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 354-359)
    - Goat Island – Bridge to Goat Island, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 360-361)
    - Goat Island – Cave of the Wind – American Side, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 362-363)
    - Horseshoe Falls – American Side - Terrapin Point, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 364)
    - Horseshoe Falls – Canadian Side, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 365-367)
    - Horseshoe Falls – Canadian side (from edge of river), 1901 (Box 7, Folder 368)
    - Horseshoe Falls – From Maid of the Mist, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 369-370)
    - Rapids – The Rapids, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 371)
    - Rapids – The Rapids above the Canadian Falls at 3 Sisters Island, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 372)
    - Rapids – Rapids Prospect Park, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 373-374)
    - Miscellaneous – Bridge - Prospect Park - Niagara Falls, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 375-378)
    - Miscellaneous – Electric Tower, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 379)
    - Miscellaneous – Fountain of Abundance – Ethnology Building, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 380)
    - Miscellaneous – Indians, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 381-382)
    - Miscellaneous – Steel Arch Bridge - from Maid of the Mist, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 383)
    - Miscellaneous – Temple of Muse, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 384)
  - Rochester
    - Bridge & Genesee Falls, undated (Box 7, Folder 385)
    - H.M. Chester's friend in Boat, undated (Box 7, Folder 386)
    - Genesee Falls, undated (Folder 387-388)